Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Judie Lannon papers, 1946-1993 and undated RL.11442
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Judie Lannon papers
1946-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11442
3.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London office first opened in 1899. Advertising executive Judie Lannon was a marketing research specialist at JWT London and the first woman named a Director in JWT's European region. Collection includes correspondence, articles and clippings, company policy and operations manuals, management training materials, texts of speeches and presentations and other printed materials. Topics include marketing research, consumer behavior, research methodologies and demographics. Companies represented include De Beers, Kellogg and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Files; Alphabetical Files.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London office first opened in 1899. Advertising executive Judie Lannon was a marketing research specialist at JWT London and the first woman named a Director in JWT's European region.
Biographical: BA, Psychology, University of Michigan. Joined JWT London, Marketing Department, 1967, became Head of Creative Research. 1989 named Director of Research and Development, JWT Europe. 1991 formed her own consulting firm.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Judie Lannon papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office records; J. Walter Thompson Company. International Offices records
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, articles and clippings, company policy and operations manuals, management training materials, texts of speeches and presentations and other printed materials. Topics include marketing research, consumer behavior, research methodologies and demographics. Companies represented include De Beers, Kellogg and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Marketing research; Marketing research -- Europe; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Kellogg Company; Unilever (Firm)
- General Files, 1985-1993 and undated; 1
  - Craft Skills Seminar, 1993 (Box 1)
  - De Beers workshop, 1988 (Box 1)
  - ESOMAR (European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research), 1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - European Association of Advertising Agencies (EAAA), 1986 (Box 1)
  - European Union--Single market, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Facts of Life: The Changing Supermarket Shopper (Rena Bartos), 1985 (Box 1)
  - "Fourth Stage Consumer" planning manifesto, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Green issues (environment), undated (Box 1)
  - Kellogg Creative Appreciation Seminar, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Kellogg Creative Planning Guidelines, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Professional Management Development Workshop, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Qualitative Research in Advertising Development (Deirdre Cordwell), 1993 (Box 2)
  - Television Production Handbook, undated (Box 2)
  - The Thompson Way, circa 1986 (Box 2)
  - Training--Board Away Day management simulation (JWT Perth), 1987 (Box 2)
  - Training--JWT Perth simulation exercises, circa 1986 (Box 2)
  - Women: The Moving Target in the UK, 1986 (Box 2)
- Alphabetical Files, 1946-1993 and undated; 2
  Scope and Contents
  "Alpha File" maintained by Lannon or her staff. Primarily journal articles, research-related clippings and other printed materials. Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - 1986 Results/1987 Projections (Box 2)
  - A.Smith--Women's Reactions to Television and Magazine Advertising for the Same Products, 1986 (Box 2)
  - A.M. Hedges--How Advertising Works short and long versions, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Addendum for Dominique's AGB speech, undated (Box 3)
  - Advertising effectiveness, 1964-1989 (Box 3)
  - Advertising in the 90s, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Advertising Research: Is It Time for a Re-Think, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Alan Hedges--Advertising: The Invisible Hand, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Alan Hedges--Research in Advertising (testing to destruction), 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Alan Swindells--Trade press presentation, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Alan Webb--How to Visualize the Appetite Appeal Benefit, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Alec Morrison--Whose Initiative?, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Allen Thomas (Chairman JWT London)--Economies of Excellence, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Allen Thomas (Chairman JWT London)--IAA speech, undated (Box 3)
  - Allen Thomas (Chairman JWT London)--Presentation to New York Board, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Allen Thomas (Chairman JWT London)--Presentation to Unilever, 1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Andrew Knight (Economist)--Retirement column, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Andy Fenning--Media in the Nineties, undated (Box 3)
  - Anne Kelleher--Philosophy and You: The Media, undated (Box 3)
  - Anne Wicks--Changing Consumer, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Anthony Praguen--TV in Europe, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Anthony Sampson--What Happened to Enterprise?, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Arnold Grisman--Image of an Imaging Company (Kodak), undated (Box 3)
  - Arnold Rockman--McCluhanism, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Arnold Toynbee excerpt, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Art Shulman--On-air recall, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Arthur Juchems--Volksbanken Reiffeisenbanken case study, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Aune-Gethe Blush--book excerpt "Identifying the Customer", 1991 (Box 3)
  - Barry Sayle (Unilever)--Geography and Geology of Consumption, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Beth Salmon (McCann-Erickson)--Qualitative research, undated (Box 3)
  - Bill Schackman--Motivations, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Bill Schackman's Bottom Lines, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Bob Mclaren--Advertising Creativity, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Brand Seminar papers (Admap), 1983 (Box 4)
  - Brian Johnson--Change and the Chief Executive, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Brian Johnson--Food and Drink Industry in Europe, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Britain Revisited excerpt, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Burt Manning--Big Ideas, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Burt Manning--Oscar Mayer Advertising, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Burt Manning--Strategy: Semper Fideles, 1982 (Box 4)
  - C. Marsh--Informants, Respondents and Citizens, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Callaghan Oherlihy--British Rail advertising testing, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Callaghan Oherlihy--What Are the Components of Profit from Advertising?, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Charles Channon--Advertising Research and Management Decision-Making, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Charles Overholser--Quality, Quantity and Thinking Real Hard, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Charles Ramond--Advertising Research, 1976 (Box 4)
  - China--AOQI anti-wrinkle cream case study, undated (Box 4)
  - Christine Restall (McCann-Erickson)--Leisure Futures, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Christine Restall, Ian Croll--The Dream Machine, undated (Box 4)
  - Christine Woesler de Panafieu--Marketing in East Germany, undated (Box 4)
  - Clifford Geertz--Thick Description excerpts, undated (Box 4)
  - Colin McDonald--Advertising research, 1979-1985 (Box 4)
  - Colin McDonald--What Have We Learnt from the Past?, undated (Box 4)
  - Colin Pendry (British American Tobacco)--Unusual Research for Unusual Advertising (Benson & Hedges), undated (Box 4)
  - Conrad Jameson--Ernest Dichter, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Culture of an Advertising Agency, undated (Box 4)
  - D. Richardson--Measuring the Role of Media in People's Lives, 1971 (Box 4)
  - D.S. Leathar--Defense-Inducing Advertising, undated (Box 4)
  - David Berger--Theory into Practice: The FCB Grid (Foote Cone Belding), 1986 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy--Megalomania and Mergers, 1987 (Box 4)
  - David Pring--Review of Third World Marketing Research, 1987 (Box 4)
  - David Seaman, Chris Blamires--The Forgotten Tribe: Research and Role of the Unemployed, undated (Box 4)
  - Donald Gilbert--Intra-Agency Relationships, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Donald Kanter--Cynical Marketing Executive, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Elisabeth Noelle-Neumann--Mass Media and Public Opinion, undated (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Hirschman--Primitive Aspects of Consumption in Modern American Society, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Nelson--Challenge of Change, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Nelson--Challenge of the New Young, 1986 (Box 4)
  - European Research (ESOMAR), 1987 (Box 4)
  - Fair Trade Mark, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Francis Fukuyama--End of History excerpt, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Gary Hamel, C.K. Prahalad--Strategic Intent, 1989 (Box 4)
  - George Garrick--Properly Evaluating the Role of TV Advertising, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Ginny Valentine--Semiotic Solutions, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Global agencies, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Grant McCracken--Celebrity endorsers, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Hans Zetterberg--The Communications Society, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Harry Phibbs--Youth in the Thatcher Era, undated (Box 4)
  - Herbert Krugman--Brain Function and Recall, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Hoover presentation, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Hughes de Jouvenel--Western Values, 1986 (Box 5)
  - J.D. Wagenaar--Chocolate presentation, 1991 (Box 5)
  - James Irvine--Media research, undated (Box 5)
  - James Irvine--Private labels "Own labels", 1979 (Box 5)
  - James Knox--The English Gentleman's Job, undated (Box 5)
  - James Ogilvy--This Postmodern Business, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Janet Mead--European Dimension, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Jay Gershuny--Scenarios, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Joe David Bellamy--Tom Wolfe, undated (Box 5)
  - John Graham, Roy Herberger--Negotiators Abroad: Don't Shoot from the Hip, 1983 (Box 5)
  - John Maloney--The First 80 Years of Advertising Research, 1987 (Box 5)
  - John Maloney--Persuasion, undated (Box 5)
  - John May--Qualitative Research, undated (Box 5)
  - John Naisbitt--Megatrends excerpt, undated (Box 5)
  - John Ward--Lifestylesss, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Judie Lannon--Notes on VALS (Values, Attitudes and Lifestyles), 1986 (Box 5)
  - Jules Goddard--Markets in Meanings, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Jules Goddard--Research styles, undated (Box 5)
  - JWT--Advertising and the Funding of the BBC, 1985 (Box 5)
  - JWT--American Lifestages, undated (Box 5)
  - JWT--List of training talks, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Kristian Palds--Hierarchy of Effects, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Laura Mazur--Brand Strategy, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Laurence Hagen--Global ads, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Lawrence Gibson--If the Question Is Copy Testing, the Answer is "No Recall", 1983 (Box 5)
  - Linda Fuller--Research panels, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Liz Levy--Over-50 Consumers, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Lynn White--Technology Assessment from the Stance of a Medieval Historian, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Martin Sorrell--Speech to Advertising Association, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Marvin Mord--Shorter Units (Television commercials), 1985 (Box 5)
  - Mary Goodyear--Five Stages of Advertising Literacy, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Mary Goodyear--Understanding Culture in International Marketing, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Maureen Pressler--The Hidden Persuaders, undated (Box 5)
  - Michael Rosser (JWT Manchester)--Researching Markets, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Neil Postman, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Norbert Homma, Jorg Ueltzhoffer--Markets and milieus, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Norm MacMaster--So What's the Big Idea?, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Norman Macrae--Entrepreneurs, 1976-1982 (Box 5)
  - P. Wack--The Future of Jobs, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Pascal Fleury--Qualitative studies, undated (Box 5)
  - Paul Atkinson--Symbolic Significance of Health Foods, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Paul Feldwick--Paradox of Price in Supermarket Shopping, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Perspectives (serial), 1991 (Box 5)
  - Peter Sampson--Qualitative Research in Europe, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Phil Bernard--Advertising Research, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Phil Gullen--The Tao of Media, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Pierre Wack (Shell Oil)--Articles on scenario planning, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Presentation on brain function, undated (Box 6)
  - Presentation to Exxon, 1991 (Box 6)
  - President Reagan's Marketing Plan, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Prosper Riley-Smith--Do Shoppers Look at Prices?, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Qualitative research, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Raimonda Boggia--Marketing Foods in Europe, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Richard Hoggart--The Reith Lectures, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Richard Vaughn--How Advertising Works, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Robert Hayes, William Abernathy--Managing Our Way to Economic Decline, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Robert Worcester--Corporate Image, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Robert Wuthnow--Moral Crisis in American Capitalism, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Roger Williams--The Executive Motivation: The Way Ahead?, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Roy Langmaid, Wendy Gordon--Branding in Television Ads, undated (Box 6)
  - SAGACITY and Empty-Nesters, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Sattar Khan--Creative Strategies in India, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Shield (deodorant soap) presentation, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Shirley Young--Copy Testing Without Magic Numbers, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Sidney Levy--Consumer Behavior, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Sonia Yuspeh--The Medium Versus the Message, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Sonia Yuspeh--PACT (Positioning, Advertising, Copy Testing), 1981 (Box 6)
  - Stephen Greyser, Eleanor May--From-Home Shopping, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Stephen Greyser, Eleanor May--Package Goods Marketing, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--Applying Research to Decision-Making, undated (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--The Changing Account Planner, undated (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--List of publications, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--New Brands, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--Public Versus Private Opinion, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
  - Stephen King--Theory of Advertisements, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Theodore Levitt--Globalization of Markets, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Theodore Levitt--Morality of Advertisements, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Timothy Joyce--How Advertising Works, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Tom Corlett--Advertising as a career, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Tom Rayfield--Why Accountancy Is Not Boring, undated (Box 6)
  - Tony Twyman--St. James and St. Martin (debate about belief and behavior theories), 1972 (Box 6)
  - Varda Langholz--Myth of Marketing, 1974 (Box 6)
  - W. Kirk MacNulty--UK Social Change, 1985 (Box 6)
  - W. Schlackman--Trained respondents, undated (Box 6)
  - Wally Olins--Presentation to The Marketing Group, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Wendy Gordon--How Do Consumers Feel Advertising Works, 1983 (Box 6)
  - William Swinyard, Charles Patti--Communications Hierarchy Framework, 1979 (Box 6)